On your mark... Set...
...في موقعك... استعداد
Have you decided yet, Kizaki-san?
ألم تقرّري بعد يا كيزاكي-سان؟
I sorta have an idea, but...
...لديّ فكرة، لكن
We're gonna have to decide soon.
سيتوجّب علينا أن نقرّر قريباً
Wow, Togano-san, you've been playing basketball since grade school?
مذهل يا توغانو-سان، كنتِ تلعبين كرة السلّة منذ المدرسة الابتدائيّة؟
Yeah. What about you?
أجل. ماذا عنكِ؟
It's always been table tennis for me.
لطالما كنتُ ألعب كرة الطاولة بالنسبة لي
I went for the volleyball club.
انتسبتُ لنادي كرة الطائرة
Did you?
حقّاً؟
On your mark...
...في موقعك
Set...
...استعداد
Next is...
...التّالية
Akebi-san?
أكيبي-سان؟
Akebi-san!
!أكيبي-سان
Yes!
!أجل
It's your turn next.
دوركِ تالياً
Oh... Right.
حسناً
Akebi Komichi! I'm ready!
!أكيبي كوميتشي! أنا جاهزة
Huh?
ماذا؟
O-On your mark...
...فـ-في موقعكِ
Set...
...استعداد
Huh?!
!ماذا؟
She's barefoot?!
!حافية؟
Jeez, I can't believe you did that.
عجباً، لا أصدّق بأنّكِ فعلتِ ذلك
Episode Three Have You Decided on a Club?
الحلقة الثّالثة هل قرّرتِ لأيّ نادٍ ستنتسبين؟
The teacher chewed me out about how I could've hurt myself.
وبّختني المعلّمة قائلة بأنّني قد أؤذي نفسي
And you had to pick up rocks as punishment, huh?
وترتّب عليك التقاط الحجارة كعقوبة
You had the fastest time out of the whole class, though.
لكن أحرزتِ أسرع وقت في الصفّ كلّه
I bet it was even faster than a boy's time.
أنا واثقة بأنّه كان أسرع من الرّقم القياسي للفتيان
Really?!
!حقّاً؟
I actually run faster when I'm barefoot!
!في الحقيقة أركض أسرع عندما أكون حافية
Hey, is Akebi Komichi-san in this class?
هل أكيبي كوميتشي-سان في هذا الصفّ؟
Um... well...
...المعذرة... في الواقع
Who are they?
من هُنّ؟
I think they're older students.
أظنّهم تلميذات أكبر سنّاً
We heard she's the only one wearing a sailor uniform to school.
سمعنا بأنّها الوحيدة التي ترتدي زيّ بحّارة رسميّ في المدرسة
Akebi-chan, Akebi-chan! Hide!
!أكيبي-تشان، أكيبي-تشان! اختبئي
There she is! The girl with the sailor uniform!
!ها هي! الفتاة ذات زيّ البحّارة الرّسمي
We saw you running out there last period.
رأيناكِ تركضين هناك في الحصّة السّابقة
Please join the track club!
!انضمّي لنادي المضمار أرجوكِ
The basketball club!
!نادي كرة السلّة
No, no! The soccer club!
!لا، لا! نادي كرة القدم
Um... I...
...المعذرة... أنا
Wow, she's all popular now.
مذهل، حقّقتْ شعبيّة الآن
I thought they were gonna...
...ظننتُ أنّهن سوف
Uh-huh.
أجل
Or... have you already picked a club?
أم... اخترتِ ناديكِ سلفاً؟
Huh? No, not yet...
...ماذا؟ لا، ليس بعد
Um—
—المعذرة
Excuse me, ladies.
المعذرة يا آنسات
I'm very sorry, but we need to prepare for our next class.
أنا آسفة جدّاً، لكن علينا التّحضير لحصّتنا التّالية
Could you try to recruit new members some other time?
هلّا حاولتُنّ ضمّ عضوات جديدات في وقت لاحق؟
Yeah, you're right.
أجل، معكِ حقّ
Sorry for barging in like that.
آسفة لدخولي فجأة هكذا
Anyway, come check out our clubs if you feel like it, okay?
على أيّ حال، تفقّدي نوادينا متى رغبتِ ذلك، اتّفقنا؟
Okay...
...حسناً
No running in the halls!
!ممنوع الجري في الأروقة
I went to check out the equestrian club, and they actually have horses.
أريد تفقّد نادي الخيّالة، ولديهم خيول في الواقع
Club Application Form
طلب انتساب لنادٍ
Name of Club I wish to join the _____ club.
اسم النّادي _____ أريد الانتساب لنادي
Wow, were they big?
هل كانت كبيرة؟
They were huge!
!كانت ضخمة
Um...
...المعذرة
Akebi-san?
أكيبي-سان؟
You have really nice legs, Tanigawa-san.
لديكِ ساقان جميلتان يا تانيغاوا-سان
Huh?
!وتبدو بشرتكِ ملساء جدّاً كالخزف
I realized it during PE earlier!
!أدركتُ ذلك أثناء حصّة التّربية البدنيّة قبل مدّة
What are you...
...ما الّذي
Do you mind if I lift your skirt?
هل تمانعين إذا رفعتُ تنّورتكِ؟
What?!
!ماذا؟
Seriously, what are you even asking?
عجباً، ما هذا الطّلب الغريب؟
Usagihara-san is running a contest to see who has the prettiest legs.
تُقيم أوساغيهارا-سان مسابقة لرؤية من لديها أجمل سيقان
Would you like to join in?
هل تودّين الانضمام؟
The teacher won't like this.
المعلّمة لن يروقها هذا
You'll get your uniforms dirty.
ستوسّخان لباسكما الرّسمي
I'll pass.
أرفض ذلك
More importantly, Akebi-san, have you decided which club you're joining?
الأهمّ يا أكيبي-سان، هل قرّرتِ ما النّادي الّذي سوف تنتسبين إليه؟
I'm still deciding, actually. They all seem really interesting.
ما زلتُ أقرّر في الواقع. كلّها تبدو مثيرة للاهتمام
So thanks for what you did earlier!
!لذا شكراً على ما فعلتِه آنذاك
No, I really didn't do anything that deserves thanks.
لا، لم أفعل شيئاً يستحقّ الشّكر حقّاً
Club applications need to be submitted this week.
يجب تسليم طلبات الانتساب للنادي هذا الأسبوع
Don't be late.
لا تتأخّري
I won't!
!حسناً
Class President Tanigawa is so serious.
رئيسة الصفّ تانيغاوا جادّة جدّاً
She just gives off this air of neatness and classic beauty.
تحيط بها هالة من الأناقة والجمال الكلاسيكي
She looked so cool setting those older girls straight earlier.
بدتْ رائعة وهي تؤدّب تلك الفتيات الأكبر سنّاً آنذاك
I feel like she could stand to be a little more playful, though.
لكن أشعر بأنّها يجب أن تكون مرِحة أكثر
Its like she's Miss. Rules and Regulations in the flesh.
إنّها صارمة في اتّباع القواعد والقوانين زيادة عن اللّزوم
I can hear you.
أسمعكِ
Could you take care of this, please?
هل بمقدوركِ الاهتمام بهذا رجاء؟
I'm not trying to be particularly serious or anything.
أنا لا أحاول أن أكون جدّية أو ما شابه
Yes, ma'am.
حاضرة
You're always such a big help.
أنتِ مُفيدة جدّاً على الدّوام
I just...
...أنا فقط
don't think anything is worth getting in trouble with the teachers over.
أنا فقط أرى أنّه لا شيء يستحقّ الدّخول في متاعب مع المعلّمات لأجله
Tanigawa-san, you're always so well-prepared.
تانيغاوا-سان، أنتِ مُتحضّرة دوماً
Okay, who knows the solution to this one?
حسناً، من يعرف حلّ هذه؟
Bye!
!وداعاً
See you tomorrow.
أراك غداً
Wake up, Kamimoku-san.
استيقظي يا كاميموكو-سان
Goodbye.
وداعاً
Goodbye, Tanigawa-san.
وداعاً يا تانيغاوا-سان
Kamimoku-san, classes are over!
!كاميموكو-سان، انتهت الدّروس
Komichi!
!كوميتشي
Akebi-san is already so popular within the class.
أكيبي-سان مشهورة من الآن في الصفّ
She's friendly and really cute,
،إنّها ودودة وظريفة حقّاً
and...
...و
Well, bye!
!حسناً، وداعاً
See you tomorrow!
!إلى اللّقاء غداً
Bye!
!وداعاً
Tanigawa-san!
!تانيغاوا-سان
She talks to me often.
كثيراً ما تتكلّم معي
Heading home now?
هل أنتِ ذاهبة إلى المنزل الآن؟
Uh, yeah...
...أجل
I noticed you were... dancing to something.
لاحظتُ أنّكِ كنتِ... ترقصين على شيء
Yeah! Fukumoto Miki-chan's solo debut song!
!أجل! أغنية الظّهور الأوّل الفرديّة لفوكوموتو ميكي-تشان
It's such a good song!
!إنّها أغنية جميلة
Fukumoto Miki
فوكوموتو ميكي
What do you think?
ما رأيكِ؟
Y-Yeah...
...أ-أجل
She's so close, I'm not hearing much of it.
إنّها قريبة جدّاً، لا أسمع مُعظمها
I'm kind of amazed you can dance to this.
أنا مندهشة من قدرتكِ على الرّقص على هذه
Huh? Really?
حقّاً؟
Yeah.
أجل
I've watched the music video over and over again to practice!
!شاهدتُ الأغنية المُصوّرة مراراً لأتمرّن
Music programs on TV, too!
!وبرامج الموسيقى في التلفزيون أيضاً
I always try to guess what she's thinking when the look on her face changes.
لطالما حاولتُ تخمين ما تفكّر فيه عندما تتغيّر تعابير وجهها
You have a very inquisitive mind.
لديكِ عقليّة فضوليّة
Thanks.
شكراً
No problem!
!العفو
What about you? Is there anything you really like?
ماذا عنكِ؟ هل من شيء تحبّينه؟
Me?
أنا؟
Yeah! I want to know more about you!
!أجل! أريد معرفة المزيد عنكِ
There's nothing that I particularly like.
لا شيء مُعيّن يجذبني في الواقع
Well, have you decided on a club yet?
حسناً، هل قرّرتِ لأيّ نادٍ ستنتسبين؟
Not... yet.
ليس... بعد
I know, right?
لا ألومكِ
There are too many to choose from! I can't pick just one!
هناك الكثير ممّا يسبّب حيرة! لا أستطيع !أن أرسو على نادٍ معيّن
It's not because there are too many I want to—
—ليس لأنّ هناك الكثير من النّوادي التي أريد
Tanigawa-san, your legs really are pretty!
!تانيغاوا-سان، ساقاكِ جميلتان
That again?
هذا من جديد؟
Please show me! I really want to see them!
!أريني أرجوكِ! أريد رؤيتهما حقّاً
No.
كلّا
Why not?
لمَ لا؟
Because it's embarrassing!
!لأنّ هذا مُحرج
You can take a picture at home and send it to me!
!يمكنكِ التقاط صورة في المنزل وإرسالها لي
How about that?
ما رأيكِ بهذه الفكرة؟
That's even more embarrassing! And it'd be saved in my history!
!هذا محرج أكثر حتّى! وستُحفَظ في سجلّي
No, huh?
لا، إذاً؟
Okay, then I'll just give you my contact info for now!
!حسناً، سأعطيكِ معلومات الاتّصال بي حاليّاً فحسب
Oh, I'll give you mine, too.
سأعطيكِ خاصّتي أيضاً
Yay!
!مرحى
Let's keep in touch all the time!
!لنبقَ على تواصل طوال الوقت
She so easily does things that I've always wanted to, but couldn't.
إنّها تفعل الأشياء بسهولة. الأشياء التي لطالما أردتُ فعلها وفشلت
See you tomorrow!
!أراكِ غداً
It makes me happy.
هذا يُسعدني
I'm home.
عُدت
Mom?
أمّي؟
Maybe she's out shopping.
ربّما خرجتْ للتسوّق
I guess it's just me.
أعتقد لا يوجد غيري
You have really nice legs.
لديكِ ساقان جميلتان
I actually took one.
التقطتُ صورة
That's so risque!
!هذا فاضح جدّاً
But it's not lewd or anything... right?
لكنّه ليس بذيئاً أو ما شابه... صحيح؟
I'm just taking a picture of myself!
!ألتقط صورة لنفسي فحسب
There's nothing lewd about it!
!لا يوجد ما هو بذيء في ذلك
And yet... my heart is pounding.
ومع ذلك... قلبي ينبض بسرعة
It's like I'm seeing a version of myself that I don't know.
وكأنّني أرى نسخة من نفسي لا أعرفها
It's... kind of fun.
هذا... ممتع بعض الشيء
So I might as well...
...لذا قد أقوم أيضاً
I'm home.
عُدت
Kei?
كي؟
Is she in her room?
هل هي في غرفتها؟
New Solutions Kanji Dictionary Japanese Dictionary Archaic Japanese Dictionary 1 Encyclopedia 2 Encyclopedia 3 Encyclopedia
قاموس الكانجيّة مع الحلول الجديدة قاموس اليابانيّة قاموس اليابانيّة القديمة موسوعة 1 موسوعة 2 موسوعة 3
I might... be a pervert.
قد أكون... منحرفة
I can't send any of these!
!لا أستطيع إرسال أيّ من هذه
Not this one... Definitely not this one.
ليست هذه... لا سيّما هذه
SEND
إرسال الملفّ؟
CANCEL
إلغاء
Kei?
كي؟
What's going on? Why haven't you changed clothes yet?
ما الّذي يجري؟ لماذا لم تبدّلي ملابسكِ بعد؟
Why?!
!لماذا؟
Wait... Wait... W-W-W-Wa—
—لحظة... لحظة... ما-ما-ما
Honey...
...أنتِ
Why are you crying?
لماذا تبكين؟
Mom...
...أمّي
This is the most embarrassing thing that could ever happen!
!هذا أكثر شيء مُحرج يحدث على الإطلاق
READ
مقروءة
Please don't show that to anyone (;人;)
من فضلكِ لا تُريها لأحد
They really are pretty!! You're good at taking selfies! Teach me how you do that!
إنّها جميلة حقّاً!! أنتِ ماهرة !في التقاط صور السّيلفي! علّميني كيفيّة فعلها
I'm good at it?
أنا ماهرة في ذلك؟
Kei, go ahead and take your bath before dinner.
كي، اذهبي واستحمّي قبل العشاء
Okay...
...حسناً
I'm so embarrassed.
أنا مُحرَجة للغاية
That book is really moving, isn't it?
هذا الكتاب مؤثّر حقّاً، أليس كذلك؟
It is.
بالفعل
Hey, Tomono-chan, do you prefer to read or write?
تومونو-تشان، هل تفضّلين المُطالعة أم الكتابة؟
Well... I do think I'd like to try writing.
في الواقع... أظنّني أودّ لو أجرّب الكتابة
And there's the aggressive literature club recruiter!
!وهناك وكيلة الانتساب لنادي الأدب العدوانيّة
What are you going to do, Tanigawa-san?
ماذا ستفعلين يا تانيغاوا-سان؟
I knew from the start that I wanted to join the literature club.
عرفتُ من البداية بأنّني أردتُ الانتساب لنادي الأدب
Yeah... I'm going to think about it a bit longer.
أجل... سأفكّر في الأمر فترة أطول
Akebi-san?
أكيبي-سان؟
What? You've already decided which club you're joining?
ماذا؟ قرّرتِ سلفاً ما النّادي الّذي ستنتسبين له؟
Here it comes!
!ها هي ذي
Okay!
!حسناً
I envy you. I just keep waffling back and forth between them all.
أحسدكِ. أظلّ أتردّد فيما بينها جميعها
Maybe I'll just join the literature club, too.
لعلّي سأنضمّ لنادي الأدب أيضاً
You shouldn't decide that way!
!لا ينبغي أن تقرّري بهذا الشّكل
If there are that many things you want to do,
إذا كانت هناك العديد من الأمور ،التي تريدين فعلها
you need to pick the one that's right.
فعليكِ أن تختاري ما هو ملائم
Kojou-san...
...كوجو-سان
Get a good look at all of them. I'll go with you.
ألقي نظرة إليها جميعها. سأذهب معكِ
Thanks!
!شكراً
Pure Heart
قلب طاهر
I never knew a school could have this many clubs.
لم أكن أعلم أنّ المدرسة تمتلك هذا العدد الكبير من النّوادي
I couldn't believe it, either.
لم أستطع تصديق ذلك أيضاً
So much for deciding.
هناك الكثير لنقرّر
That just gave me even more things I want to try!
منحَني ذلك المزيد من الأشياء الّتي !أريد تجربتها فحسب
Sorry I wasn't much help.
آسفة لأنّني لم أكن مفيدة كثيراً
Huh?
!لماذا تقولين ذلك؟ لقد استمتعتُ كثيراً
I'll go home and try to really think it through.
سأعود للمنزل وأحاول التّفكير في الأمر مليّاً
Thank you so much for doing this with me!
!شكراً جزيلاً لكِ على القيام بهذا معي
Sure.
العفو
I hope you find a club that's perfect for you.
آمل أن تجدي نادياً مثاليّاً لكِ
It's really pouring.
إنّها تُمطر
You're soaked, Kojou-san.
تبلّلتِ تماماً يا كوجو-سان
I'm sorry. If you hadn't been visiting clubs with me...
...أنا آسفة. لو لم تزوري النّوادي معي
No, it's okay.
لا، لا عليكِ
I'm more worried about you. Aren't you cold in those thin clothes?
أنا قلقة أكثر عليكِ. ألستِ بردانة بهذه الملابس الرّقيقة؟
I'm totally—
—أنا تماماً
See? Take those off before you catch a cold.
!رأيتِ؟ اخلعيها قبل أن تُصابي بنزلة برد
Okay.
حسناً
This is a little embarrassing.
هذا مُحرج قليلاً
It's so warm.
هذا دافئ جدّاً
Thanks!
!شكراً
You look a little more grown-up in that.
تبدين ناضجة أكثر بهذا
Oh, that's...
...هذا
Beyond the Blue Sky
وراء السّماء الزرقاء
Imai Tsutomu
إيماي تسوتومو
It's the novel I'm going to read at the club's next reading.
إنّها الرّواية التي سأقرأها في جلسة المُطالعة التّالية للنادي
A reading...
...مُطالعة
That sounds fun!
!يبدو هذا ممتعاً
Hardly.
بالكاد
It'll be my first time. I can't read in front of people.
ستكون المرّة الأولى لي. لا يمكنني المُطالعة أمام النّاس
You'll be fine!
!ستكونين بخير
Have you done that before?
هل سبقَ وفعلتِ ذلك؟
Yeah... though it was just for my little sister.
أجل... رغم أنّ ذلك كان لأجل أختي الصّغرى
I love looking down at Kao's head while she's looking at the book.
أحبّ النّظر إلى رأس كاو بينما تنظر هي للكتاب
I'd like to hear it, too.
أودّ الاستماع لذلك أيضاً
The way your sister does.
مثلما تفعل أختكِ
Sure.
بالتأكيد
You'll have to tell me what the harder kanji are, okay?
سيكون عليكِ أن تخبريني ما هي الكانجي الأصعب، اتّفقنا؟
Beyond the Blue Sky by Imai Tsutomu.
وراء السّماء الزرقاء من تأليف إيماي تسوتومو
"With five minutes before the bell rings,
،قبل خمس دقائق من قرع الجرس"
I hurriedly clear off the top of my desk.
سارعتُ لتنظيف سطح مكتبي
It's been six months since the accident.
مضت ستّة أشهر منذ الحادثة
As I hobble along on my crutches,
،وبينما أعرج على عكّازتي
a large spider..."
"...عنكبوت كبير
"A large spider languidly passes me by.
"مرّ عنكبوت منّي ببطء
I look up at the sky.
نظرتُ إلى السّماء
'How lucky the clouds are. They're so free...'
...كم هي الغيوم محظوظة. إنّها حُرّة
Tomorrow is the final round of the prefectural tournament.
غداً الجولة الأخيرة من دوري المُحافظات
I was supposed to be in it.
كان يُفترض أن أكون فيها
'Hey!'
!أنت
A voice that sounds much too deep to be a middle schooler calls me from behind..."
صوت يبدو أعمق بكثير من نِداء طالبة "...مدرسة إعداديّة لي من الخلف
"Hey!"
"!أنت"
"Slow, relaxed footsteps approach me, resounding quietly.
دنَتْ منّي خطوات أقدام هادئة وبطيئة"
Then, suddenly, someone enters my field of vision.
ثمّ دخل شخصٌ مجال نظري فجأة
'I know a club that's perfect for you!'"
"!أعرف نادياً مثاليّاً لك"
Huh?
ماذا؟
Mom?
أمّي؟
Uh... sorry.
آسفة
It stopped raining.
توقّفت المطر عن الهطول
I am so sorry! I must have been heavy.
أنا آسفة جدّاً! لا بدّ أنّني كنتُ ثقيلة
Not at all! That actually made me happy!
!إطلاقاً! أسعدني ذلك في الواقع
My sister always says my mom's lap is comfier than mine.
تقول أختي دوماً أنّ حضن أمّي مريح أكثر من حضني
I can't stand it!
!لا أستطيع تحمّل ذلك
So how did my lap feel?
لذا كيف بدا حضني؟
Y-Yeah... It felt nice.
أ-أجل... بدا مريحاً
And...
...و
So did your reading.
طالعتِ إذاً
Akebi-san, why don't we take a look at one last club?
أكيبي-سان، لمَ لا نلقي نظرة إلى نادٍ أخير؟
Good morning.
صباح الخير
Morning!
!صباح الخير
Akebi-chan, it's not too late!
!أكيبي-تشان، لم يفت الأوان كثيراً
Join the softball club with me! We'll aim for the nationals!
!انضمّي لنادي الكرة الليّنة معي !سنطمح للبطولة الوطنيّة
Roubai allows students to join multiple clubs.
تسمح أكاديميّة روباي للتلميذات الانضمام لنوادٍ عديدة
Wanna climb some mountains?
أتريدين تسلّق بعض الجبال؟
Those both sound like fun,
،كلاهما يبدوان ممتعين
but I found the club that's right for me.
لكن وجدتُ النّادي الملائم لي
I-I see...
...هـ-هكذا إذاً
Really? What is it?
حقّاً؟ ما هو؟
Good morning.
صباح الخير
Oh, good morning, Tanigawa-san!
!صباح الخير يا تانيغاوا-سان
Morning!
!صباح الخير
I decided which club I'm joining.
قرّرتُ النّادي الّذي سأنتسب له
Photography.
التّصوير
That's perfect for you!
!إنّه مثاليّ لكِ
Well? What did you decide on, Akebi-chan?
حسناً؟ ما النّادي الّذي اخترتِه يا أكيبي-تشان؟
Tell us! Tell us!
!أخبرينا! أخبرينا
The drama club!
!نادي الدراما